Finding aid for the Alma Hawkins papers, 1919-1998 LSC.2182
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 4: Dance therapy, 1964-1997
  - American Journal of Dance Therapy, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Dance Therapy Certification, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Dance Therapy Films: Notes (1 of 3), 1970 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Dance Therapy Films: Notes (2 of 3), undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Dance Therapy Films: Notes (3 of 3), undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Dance Therapy Films: Participant Notes, Undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Dance Therapy Films: Participant Release Forms, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Dance Therapy Films: Photos, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Dance Therapy Films: Script, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Grad Council of Dance Movement Educators (1 of 3), 1979-1986 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Grad Council of Dance Movement Educators (2 of 3), 1980-1985 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Grad Council of Dance Movement Educators (3 of 3), 1972-1982 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Patient Evaluations (1 of 6), 1964 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Patient Evaluations (2 of 6), 1966 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Patient Evaluations (3 of 6), 1966 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Patient Evaluations (4 of 6), undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Patient Evaluations (5 of 6), undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Patient Evaluations (6 of 6), undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Patient Interviews: Relaxation, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Research: Research Articles, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Research Projects and Proposals, 1966-1975 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Research and Sources, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - UCLA Neuropsychiatric Institute (2 of 2), undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - UCLA Neuropsychiatric Institute (1 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Series 5: Personal papers, 1919-1998
  This series contains Hawkin's personal materials, and includes family genealogies, birth certificates, and photos, scrapbooks, and yearbooks from her adolescence and young adulthood. Also included are professional portraits and candid photographs, including photos from Hawkins' attendance at the summer dance school at Bennington College, which feature Martha Graham, Doris Humphrey, Charles Weidman, and John Martin. The series also includes the numerous awards, plaques, and trophies Hawkins' was given for her professional service to the dance community. Finally, the series contains documents relating to Hawkins' funeral, obituary, and memorial service at UCLA.
  This is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  RESTRICTED ACCESS: Use of audio and moving image material requires production of listening and viewing copies.
  - 80th Birthday Council of Dance Administrators Scrapbook, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - 80th Birthday Scrapbook, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 90th Birthday Scrapbook, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Address and Phone Books, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Alice Hawkins: Diploma from University of Minnesota, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - American Dance Therapy Association Award, undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - American Dance Therapy Association Award Plaque, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Artworks, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Artworks, undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Audiovisual materials: American Contemporaries LP record, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Audiovisual materials: Tortuga del Sol videocassette (VHS), undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Audiovisual materials: National Dance Association Honor videocassette (VHS), 1995 (Box 35, Folder 3-4)
  - Audiovisual materials: 90th Birthday Party videocassette (VHS) (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Audiovisual materials: Council of Dance Educators Workshop videocassette (Betamax), 1980 (Box 35, Folder 6-7)
  - Audiovisual materials: Interview with Alwin Nikolais videocassette (Betamax), undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Audiovisual materials: Interview with Murray Louis videocassette (Betamax), 1987 (Box 35, Folder 9-10)
  - Audiovisual materials: Dan and Dale sound cassette, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Audiovisual materials: Sylvia Fein sound cassette, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Audiovisual materials: Dr. Joseph Bogen sound cassette, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Audiovisual materials: Dr. Joboson sound cassette, undated (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Audiovisual materials: Poetry sound cassette, undated (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Audiovisual materials: Robert Ornstein sound cassettes, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 12-16)
  - Audiovisual materials: Summer Session sound cassettes, undated (Box 35, Folder 24-25)
  - Audiovisual materials: Sybil Shearer sound cassettes, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 21-22)
  - Audiovisual materials: Mentor Group Discussions sound cassette, undated (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Audiovisual materials: Awin Nikolais Imagery sound cassette (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Audiovisual materials: Murray Louis Interview sound cassette, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Audiovisual materials: Notes-to-self sound cassette, undated (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - Audiovisual materials: Speech Intuitive Process as a Force for Change sound cassettes, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - Audiovisual materials: Unidentified sound cassettes, undated (Box 35, Folder 30-33)
  - Awards and Honors, 1972-1989 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Awards: American College Dance Festival, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Awards: American Dance Therapy Association, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Awards: California Dance Educators Association, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Awards: LA Area Dance Alliance, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Awards: LA Area Dance Alliance, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Awards: LA Cultural Center, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Awards: National Association for Sports and Physical Education, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Awards: National Dance Association, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Awards: National Dance Association, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Awards: National Dance Association Plaudit Award, undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Awards: Perry-Mansfield School of Dance Scholarship, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Awards: UCLA Teaching Award, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Awards: University of Missouri Women's Centennial, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Birth Certificate, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Choreography: High School Play Programs, 1930 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Clay Sculpture Award, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - College Diary, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Columbia Teachers College PhD material, 1949-1952 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University Commencement, 1932 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1958-1997 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1987-1998 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Council of Dance Educators Association Award, 1979-1980 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Dance Chair Deskplate, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Dance magazine Autographed Copy, 1973 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Diplomas: Columbia University Doctor of Education, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Diplomas: Columbia University Masters, 1932 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Diplomas: Rolla High School, 1923 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Diplomas: Rolla Public Grammar School, 1919 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Diplomas: University of Missouri Bachelor of Science, 1927 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Family History: Family Tree, undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Family History: Marriage License, undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Graduation Commencement Gown, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - High School Scrapbook, 1919-1923 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - High School Yearbooks, 1919-1923 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Household Documents, 1996-1997 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - List of Awards, undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Medical Literature (1 of 2), undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Medical Literature (2 of 2), 1994-1996 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - National Dance Association Heritage Award, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Obituary Draft, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Organizational Membership, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Photos: 80th Birthday, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Photos: 85th Birthday, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Photos: 90th Birthday, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Photos: 1992 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Photos: Award Ceremonies, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Photos: Bennington College Dance, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Photos: Candid Photos (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Photos: Early Dance Photos, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Photos: Early Family Photos, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Photos: Early Photos of Hawkins, undated (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Photos: Friends, Family, Colleagues, undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Photos: Headshots, undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Photos: House, undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Photos: John Martin, undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Photos: June 16, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Photos: Mark Harmel Photo Shoot, undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Photos: Other People, undated (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Photos: Perry-Mansfield Performing Arts Camp, undated (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Photos: Professional Photography, undated (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Photos: Retirement Party, undated (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Photos: Sybil Shearer, undated (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Photos: UCLA Award, undated (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Photos: UCLA Campus, undated (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Photos: UCLA Commencement, undated (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Photos: UCLA Dance Concerts, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Photos: UCLA Retirement Party, undated (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Photos: UCLA Teaching, undated (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Photos: Xmas 1988 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Sheet Music, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Signature Stamp, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Sybil Shearer: Press Material, 1993 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Sybil Shearer: Writings, 1976-1990 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Sybil Shearer: Autobiography Manuscript (1 of 2), undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Sybil Shearer: Autobiography Manuscript (2 of 2), undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Teachers Certificate Missouri Public Schools, 1923 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - UCLA Distinguished Service Medal, undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - UCLA Distinguished Service Plaque, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - UCLA Memorial Service, 1998 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - University of Missouri Yearbook, 1923-1927 (Box 29, Folder 1)